Jessie Lloyd O'Connor Papers, 1850-1988
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES II. CORRESPONDENCE 1875-1988
  - Friends and associates
    - Ameringer, Freda1941-77 (Box 40, Folder 15)
    - Anderson, Cornelia1946-83, undated (Box 40, Folder 16)
    - Anderson, Jennie (Box 40)
      [see General/business-Charity for individuals]
    - Appleton, Clyde1961-88, undated (Box 41, Folder 1)
    - Arnold, Maria (Box 41)
      [see SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES-Political prisoners and refugees]
    - Aronson, Jim1956-82, undated (Box 41, Folder 2)
    - Ault, Harry, Kay (Minnie), and Mickey1944-74 (Box 41, Folder 3)
    - A1925-88, undated (Box 41, Folder 4)
    - Balassa, Alice and Leslie1959-86, undated (Box 41, Folder 5)
    - Balch, Emily Greene1945-58 (Box 41, Folder 6)
    - Baldwin, Charlescirca 1934-circa 1937, undated (Box 41, Folder 7)
    - Ball, Lee and Maria1946-82, undated (Box 41, Folder 8)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Methodist Federation for Social Service/Social Action]
    - Barnard, Harry1949-52 (Box 41, Folder 9)
    - Bauman, Jeffrey1960-79 (Box 41, Folder 10)
    - Bazell, Bertha1948-56, undated (Box 41, Folder 11)
    - Beaumont, George1954-64 (Box 41, Folder 12)
    - Beier, Helen1977-80 (Box 41, Folder 13)
    - Belfrage, Cedric and Marycirca 1959-76 (Box 41, Folder 14)
    - Benedict, Nancy1961-66 (Box 41, Folder 15)
    - Berger, Minnie and Philip1959-61 (Box 41, Folder 16)
    - Bernhardt, Mathias1975-76 (Box 41, Folder 17)
    - Bernstein, Larry and Patty1953-88, undated (Box 41, Folder 18)
    - Bird, Frances1922, 1957-68 (Box 41, Folder 19)
    - [Bird?], Margaret ("Peg")circa 1918, 1920 (Box 41, Folder 20)
    - Blanc, Elsie1930 (Box 41, Folder 21)
    - Blanchard, Monette1966-69, undated (Box 41, Folder 22)
    - Blankenhorn, Ann and George1949-65, undated (Box 41, Folder 23)
    - Bloor, Ella Reeve1935-47, undated (Box 41, Folder 24)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Lloyd, Henry Demarest]
    - Blossom, Frederick and Bertie Lee1966-77, undated (Box 41, Folder 25)
    - Blum, Richard and Ernestine1944-84 (Box 41, Folder 26)
    - Boe, Jean Wheeler1952-77, undated (Box 41, Folder 27)
    - Bohanon, Eunice Blake1946-85 (Box 41, Folder 28)
    - Boner, Carol Stevens1965-67 (Box 41, Folder 29)
    - Booth, Minnie1944-74 (Box 41, Folder 30)
    - Borodin, Michael1938, 1945 (Box 41, Folder 31)
    - Boschan, Paul1939-50, undated (Box 41, Folder 32)
      [see also SERIES V. SUBJECTS -Political prisoners and refugees-Boschan, Paul]
    - Boudin, Jean and Leonard (includes a few letters from Kathy Boudin)1954-86, undated (Box 42, Folder 1)
    - Bowen, Louise de Koven1941, 1962 (Box 42, Folder 2)
    - Boyden, Polly1942-54 (Box 42, Folder 3)
    - Braden, Anne and Carl1956-88, undated (Box 42, Folder 4-5)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Southern Conference Educational Fund]
    - Braden, Beth1976-88, undated (Box 42, Folder 6)
    - Braden, Jim and Mandy1956-86, undated (Box 42, Folder 7)
    - Bradley, Anne Parmelee and Phil1945-88, undated (Box 42, Folder 8)
    - Briggs, Lucy Barnard1948-87 (Box 42, Folder 9)
    - Briner, Mary Ramsay1940-66 (Box 42, Folder 10)
    - Brown, Carol1954-83 (Box 42, Folder 11)
    - Brown, Hilary and Harrison1938-80, undated (Box 42, Folder 12)
    - Brown, Stattie May and Bo1946-86, undated (Box 42, Folder 13)
    - Buckler, Helen (Bobby)1942-83, undated (Box 43, Folder 1)
    - Buehrer, Bernardine and Edwin1944-61, undated (Box 43, Folder 2)
    - Buhle, Paul1979-88, undated (Box 43, Folder 3)
    - Burgess, Helen and Andy1956-87, undated (Box 43, Folder 4)
    - Burgess, Ruth1954-84, undated (Box 43, Folder 5)
    - Busiek, Dorothy D.1964-76 (Box 43, Folder 6)
    - Byloff, Dorothy1957-69 (Box 43, Folder 7)
    - B1929-87, undated (Box 43, Folder 8)
    - Cajkova, Helena1966-77 (Box 43, Folder 9)
    - Campbell, Connie1977-88, undated (Box 43, Folder 10)
    - Campbell, Kenneth N.1956-64 (Box 43, Folder 11)
    - Campbell, Mary1973-78, undated (Box 43, Folder 12)
    - Cann, Margaret1954, 1972-79, undated (Box 43, Folder 13)
    - Carner, Lucy Perkins1956-83, undated (Box 43, Folder 14)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-WILPF]
    - Carter, Dick1948-88, undated (Box 43, Folder 15)
    - Carter, Helen1922-24, 1948-80s, undated (Box 43, Folder 16)
    - Carter, Margaret, Jack, Lawrence, and Nancy1948-88, undated (Box 43, Folder 17)
    - Cesare, Ann1948-[71?], undated (Box 43, Folder 18)
    - Chapman, Dwight1921-27, undated (Box 44, Folder 1-2)
    - Chappell, Winnie1943-44 (Box 44, Folder 3)
    - Claiborne, Bob1948-66 (Box 44, Folder 4)
    - Clark, Janice and Kempton (Shethar Real Estate and Insurance)1961-78, undated (Box 44, Folder 5)
    - Clark, Ruth M.1967, 1976 (Box 44, Folder 6)
    - Cloud, Lucy Anne and Robert Moore1962, 1973 (Box 44, Folder 7)
    - Cobb, Georgia, William, and Anne1949-63 (Box 44, Folder 8)
    - Cohen, Ruth and Sid1946-52 (Box 44, Folder 9)
    - Corkran, Rusty and David1967, undated (Box 44, Folder 10)
    - Cowart, Bobby and George1956-86, undated (Box 44, Folder 11)
    - Craig, Maxine1947-56 (Box 44, Folder 12)
    - Crane, Sylvia1964-86, undated (Box 44, Folder 13)
    - Crawford, Ahleen and Randall1945-57, undated (Box 44, Folder 14)
    - Crearer, James (Box 44)
      [see SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Homes and real estate-- Jamaica (Bu Saaba)]
    - Criley, Dick1961-85, undated (Box 44, Folder 15)
    - Crowley, Barbara and Robert1961-76, undated (Box 44, Folder 16)
    - Cruden, Janet and Robert1947-88, undated (Box 44, Folder 17)
    - Curtis, Sybil1964-71 (Box 44, Folder 18)
    - Cush, Emmett Pat1938-55 (Box 44, Folder 19)
    - C1913-83, undated (Box 44, Folder 20)
    - Davidson, Evelyn and Ray1956-88, undated (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Davidson, Marion S. (Box 45)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Claude Williams Support Committee]
    - Davis, Barbara1944, 1981-82, undated (Box 45, Folder 2)
    - Davis, Marian, Horace, and Mina1929-88, undated (Box 45, Folder 3)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Marian Rubins Davis Scholarship Fund]
    - Davis, Natalie Zemon and Chandler1957-88 (Box 45, Folder 4)
    - Davis, Quentin and Herbert1961, undated (Box 45, Folder 5)
    - Day, Bonnie and Leon1958-83, undated (Box 45, Folder 6)
    - Deemer, Albert and Estelle1943?-49 (Box 45, Folder 7)
    - Dellinger, David (Box 45)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATON FILES--Liberation]
    - Dellitch, Helen1936-37 (Box 45, Folder 8)
    - De Maio, Ernest and Mary1948-88, undated (Box 45, Folder 9)
    - Derr, Mary Sebring1954-66 (Box 45, Folder 10)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Education--Smith College--Alumnae activities]
    - Destler, Chester and Katharine1937-69 (Box 45, Folder 11)
    - De Vries, Lini1957-79, undated (Box 45, Folder 12)
    - Dewey, John and Roberta1949 (Box 45)
      [see SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Homes and other real estate--Jamaica]
    - De Wolfe, Genie1946-1949 (Box 45, Folder 13)
    - Dezla, Sophia (Box 45)
      [see Glassgold, Cook and Sophia Dezla]
    - Dieckmann, Annetta1943-66 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-YWCA]
    - Dizard, Debbie1960-82 (Box 45, Folder 15)
    - Djordje, Smiljanic1951-52 (Box 45, Folder 16)
    - Dombrowski, James A.1975-81 (Box 45, Folder 17)
    - Douglas, Scott1977-88, undated (Box 45, Folder 18)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Claude Williams Support Committee]
    - Dreikurs, Sadie1942-87, undated (Box 45, Folder 19)
    - Drew, George and Myra[1945?-85?], undated (Box 45, Folder 20)
    - Drndic, Ljubo (Box 45)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Yugoslav Information Center]
    - Dubbs, Jean1924-25, undated (Box 45, Folder 21)
    - Durr, Virginia Foster1962-86, undated (Box 45, Folder 22)
    - Dushkin, Dorothy Smith, David, and Lelah1927-85 (Box 45, Folder 23)
      [see also General/business-Children-Schools and camps-Kinhaven; and SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES -Kinhaven]
    - Dyett, Jim and Pat1937-50, undated (Box 46, Folder 1)
    - D1920-88, undated (Box 46, Folder 2)
    - Edwards, Emily1945-79, undated (Box 46, Folder 3)
    - Edwards, Richard1978, undated (Box 46, Folder 4)
    - Elber, Irwin and Sara1940-84, undated (Box 46, Folder 5)
    - Elliot, Dan and Grace1931-32 (Box 46, Folder 6)
    - Ellis, Franklin and Marcella1946-78, undated (Box 46, Folder 7)
    - Ellison, Theda1919-60, undated (Box 46, Folder 8)
    - Emerson, Josephine1964-67 (Box 46, Folder 9)
    - Ewer, W.N. (Box 46)
      [see SERIES III. WRITINGS--London Daily Herald]
    - E1919-87, undated (Box 46, Folder 10)
    - Falkoff, Fontaine[1954?]-83 (Box 46, Folder 11)
    - Falkowski, Ed1963-83 (Box 46, Folder 12)
    - Farmer, Fyke1950-57, undated (Box 46, Folder 13)
    - Farmer, Renee and Jack1963-79 (Box 46, Folder 14)
    - Feijo, Isabel and Manuel1957-76, undated (Box 46, Folder 15)
    - Fenner, Frances1956-88 (Box 46, Folder 16)
    - Ferry, Elinor1953-85 (Box 46, Folder 17)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Emergency Civil Liberties Committee]
    - Fichter, Evelyn and William L. (Chick)1951-84, undated (Box 46, Folder 18)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Women's International League for Peace and Freedom, Providence Chapter]
    - Fichter, Margallen and Donn1962-85 (Box 46, Folder 19)
    - Figueiredo, Eulalia (Box 46)
      [see Papaandreu, Eulalia Figueiredo]
    - Flamm, Irving H.1950-60 (Box 46, Folder 20)
    - Florance, Eleanor1924-68, undated (Box 46, Folder 21)
    - Flynn, Elizabeth Gurley1954-59 (Box 47, Folder 1)
    - Foreman, Clark and Mairi1953-76 (Box 47, Folder 2)
    - Forsythe, James and Anne1934-47, undated (Box 47, Folder 3)
    - Foth, Annette E. (Box 47)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--People's Institute of Applied Religion]
    - Fowler, Eleanor1966-83 (Box 47, Folder 4)
    - Frampton, Anna1948-65, undated (Box 47, Folder 5)
    - France, Clemens (includes enclosed letter from Eulalia Figueiredo Papaandreu)1952-56, undated (Box 47, Folder 6)
      [see also Papaandreu, Eulalia Figueiredo]
    - Friedman, Dorothy1952-86 (Box 47, Folder 7)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-- WILPF]
    - Fuchs, Rose1939-86 (Box 47, Folder 8)
    - Fussell, Paul1961, 1963 (includes enclosed 1916 letter from Benjamin Karr and articles re: Ford Peace Expedition) (Box 47, Folder 9)
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Articles and essays-Alphabetical-"The Story of the Ford Peace Ship"]
    - Fcirca 1922-77, undated (Box 47, Folder 10)
    - Gage-Colby, Ruth1947-77, undated (Box 47, Folder 11)
    - Garrigue, Jean1953-69 (Box 47, Folder 12)
    - Gehlke, Helen1940-67, undated (Box 47, Folder 13)
    - Geick, Sue Jones1953-86 (Box 47, Folder 14)
    - Glassgold, Cook, and Sophia Dezla1966-87 (Box 47, Folder 15)
    - Goldberg, Ruth (Box 47)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Southern Conference Educational Fund]
    - Gonzales, Jorge E.1957, undated (Box 47, Folder 16)
    - Goode, Ruth1984?-87, undated (Box 47, Folder 17)
    - Graves, Anna Melissa1951-63, undated (Box 47, Folder 18-19)
    - Gray, Annie E. Oakman (includes enclosure, 1935 postcard from Eliot White)1947-54 (Box 47, Folder 20)
    - Greenfield, Margaret[1937?]-82 (Box 47, Folder 21)
    - Grierson, Margaret Storrs1945-88, undated (Box 47, Folder 22)
      [see also General/business--Archives and libraries--Sophia Smith Collection]
    - Griffith, Margaret Davenport (Davie) and Ernest1923-85, undated (Box 48, Folder 1)
    - Gruen, Sonia Strauss and Kurt1937-75 (Box 48, Folder 2)
    - Gruliow, Leo1982, 1988 (Box 48, Folder 3)
    - Guernsey, Adrienne and Tom1969-74, undated (Box 48, Folder 4)
    - Guernsey, Elsa, George, John, and Judy1939-87, undated (Box 48, Folder 5)
    - Gustafson, Elton and Sarah (Box 48)
      [see General/business--Children--Schools and camps--Timberline, An Interracial Camp for Boys and Girls (Jewett, NY)]
    - G1923-84, undated (Box 48, Folder 6)
    - Haag, Sofia1927-69, undated (Box 48, Folder 7-8)
    - Haakman, Louise1964?-74 (Box 49, Folder 1)
    - Haas, Eugenundated (Box 49, Folder 2)
    - Haase, Rudy (Martin R.)1957-88, undated (Box 49, Folder 3)
    - Hackett, Frances and Albert1967-87, undated (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Haessler, Carl and Lucy1930-88 (Box 49, Folder 5)
      [see also SERIES III. WRITINGS-Federated Press]
    - Haffenreffer, Carl W. and Carolyn1950-72 (Box 49, Folder 6)
    - Hahn, Nancy and Mannel1954-61, undated (Box 49, Folder 7)
    - Hamann, Mary Foss1976-84, undated (Box 49, Folder 8)
    - Hamilton, Helen P.1919-41, undated (Box 49, Folder 9)
    - Hanscom, William and Opal1952, 1977-80 (Box 49, Folder 10)
    - Hansen, Harry1944 (Box 49, Folder 11)
    - Hansome, Beulah Ione and Marius1956-64 (Box 49, Folder 12)
    - Haraszti, Zoltan1923-25, 1958, undated (Box 49, Folder 13)
    - Harper, Allan G., Kathleen, and Ernest1932, 1943, 1959 (Box 49, Folder 14)
    - Harrison, Persis J.1945-52 (includes enclosure, letter from Lola Maverick (Lloyd) to Harrison, Oct or Nov 1892) (Box 49, Folder 15)
    - Hart, Oliver B.1920-21 (Box 49, Folder 16)
    - Hart, Pearl1953, 1958, 1970 (Box 49, Folder 17)
    - Harvey, Iris and Phyllis1946-80, undated (Box 49, Folder 18)
    - Hastings, Marguerita1953-56 (Box 49, Folder 19)
    - Havens, Louise1959-78, undated (Box 49, Folder 20)
    - Hays, Lee1940-55, undated (photograph of Lee Hays and Mary Seeger enclosed) (Box 49, Folder 21)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Peoples Artists]
    - Hayward, Beatrice1949-51, undated (Box 49, Folder 22)
    - Helms, Judy1956-60 (Box 49, Folder 23)
    - Hennacy, Ammon1962-69 (Box 49, Folder 24)
    - Herbst, Josephine1943?-68, undated (Box 49, Folder 25)
    - Herford, Beatrice1948-50 (Box 50, Folder 1)
    - Herring, Frances1963-88 (Box 50, Folder 2)
    - Higbee, Alice1954-66, undated (Box 50, Folder 3)
    - Hilton, Josephine M.1957, 1959, 1974-86, undated (Box 50, Folder 4)
    - Horton, Myles (Box 50)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Highlander Folk School/Highlander Research and Education Center]
    - Houghton, Sarah Meyerson and Harold1971-89, undated (Box 50, Folder 5)
    - Howells, Kay, Jack, and Anne1955-84 (Box 50, Folder 6)
    - Huberman, Leo1941-66 (Box 50, Folder 7)
    - Hunt, Carolyn1981-87, undated (Box 50, Folder 8)
    - Huntoon, Tookey and Ann1952-circa 1961 (Box 50, Folder 9)
    - Hutchins, Grace1931-65, undated (Box 50, Folder 10)
    - H1823-88, undated (Box 50, Folder 11)
    - Ickes, Betty and Bobby1953-65, undated (Box 50, Folder 12)
    - Imbrie, Nell1968-69 (Box 50, Folder 13)
    - Inglis, Agnes (Box 50)
      [see General/business--Archives and libraries--University of Michigan, Labadie Collection]
    - Ives, Ellen, Steve, and Woody1964-86, undated (Box 50, Folder 14)
    - Jasinski, Eugene and Perihan1970-89 (Box 50, Folder 15)
    - Johansen, Agnes M.1949, 1959, 1969, 1972 (Box 50, Folder 16)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL--Financial and legal material--The Lloyd Properties]
    - Johnson, Frank and Doris1942-79, undated (Box 50, Folder 17)
    - Johnson, Roberta and Lewis1958-71 (Box 50, Folder 18)
    - Johnstone, Mary McAvoy (Box 50)
      [see McAvoy, Muriel]
    - Jonas, Renee Lovas1960-72 (Box 50, Folder 19)
    - Jones, Ellis O. and Ellis O, Jr.1929-67 (Box 50, Folder 20)
    - Jones, Hays and Rosamond1929, 1940-84, undated (Box 50, Folder 21)
    - Jones, Sue and Sheila (Box 50)
      [see Geick, Sue Jones and Schonbrun, Sheila Jones]
    - Josephson, Hannah and Matty1953-77 (Box 50, Folder 22)
    - J1921-87, undated (Box 50, Folder 23)
    - Karolyi, Catherine1958-59 (Box 50, Folder 24)
    - Kasdon, Nora Sauer1945-77 (Box 50, Folder 25)
    - Kaufman, Enit1947-55, undated (Box 51, Folder 1)
    - Keck, George Fred1943-56, undated (Box 51, Folder 2)
    - Kelly, Frances1963-66 (Box 51, Folder 3)
    - Kiehel, Connie and Fay1948-55, undated (Box 51, Folder 4)
    - Knoch, Leland and Anne1932-43, undated (Box 51, Folder 5)
    - Knutsen, Ruth1943, 1949, undated (Box 51, Folder 6)
    - Koger, Grace, Harry, and children1950-83 (Box 51, Folder 7)
    - Komorowski, Conrad and Naomi1939-70, undated (Box 51, Folder 8)
    - Kowal, Gertrude1979-85, undated (Box 51, Folder 9)
    - Kuch, Dick1948-52, undated (Box 51, Folder 10)
    - Kunvari, Lilla and Bella1968-82 (Box 51, Folder 11)
    - Kuykendall, Mabel1947-68 (Box 51, Folder 12)
    - Kyle, Ruth Johnson1955-81, undated (Box 51, Folder 13)
    - K1922-88, undated (Box 51, Folder 14)
    - Lamont, Corliss and Helen1931-86, undated (Box 51, Folder 15)
    - Lane, Myrtle1963 (Box 51, Folder 16)
    - Langer, Elinor1959, 1976-88 (Box 51, Folder 17)
    - Laning, Claire1940-62, undated (Box 51, Folder 18)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Homes and other real estate-- Jamaica (Bu Saaba)]
    - Larkin, Katherine1982-88 (Box 51, Folder 19)
    - Larkin, Margaret (Box 51)
      [see Maltz, Margaret Larkin and Albert]
    - Lazareff, Maria1954-63 (Box 51, Folder 20)
    - Lazarus, Frieda Langer1944-68 (Box 51, Folder 21)
    - Lee, Bonnie and J.A.1960, 1976-85, undated (Box 51, Folder 22)
    - Leicester, Agnes1976-80, undated (Box 51, Folder 23)
    - Leleu, Michel1954-70 (Box 51, Folder 24)
    - Lens, Sidney and Shirley1967-79? (Box 51, Folder 25)
    - Leslie, Kenneth1947-61 (Box 51, Folder 26)
    - Liggett, Tom and Sue (Box 51)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--World Peace News]
    - Lipschitz, Deanne1957-61 (Box 51, Folder 27)
    - Liveright, Herman and Betty1969-88, undated (Box 51, Folder 28)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES -Highlander Folk School/Highlander Research and Education Center]
    - Loeb, Dorothy1945-71, undated (Box 51, Folder 29)
    - Loeb, Gertrude1945-79, undated (Box 51, Folder 30)
    - Lomonosoff, Raissa1949-60 (Box 51, Folder 31)
    - Lord, Frances Curran1957-88, undated (Box 51, Folder 32)
    - Lubka, Lewis and Nancy1963-76 (Box 51, Folder 33)
    - Luscomb, Florence1953-76, undated (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - Lynd, Helen, Robert, and Staughton1965-74, undated (Box 52, Folder 2)
    - Lytle, Elisabeth and Bill1964-87 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - Lyttle, Bradford1962-88 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - L1918-84, undated (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - MacDougall, Curtis1953-82, undated (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - MacEwan, Alan and Mary1960-88 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - MacMahon, Edna1947-48, undated (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - MacMartin, Helen1952-58 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - Mahoney, Clara and Gerald1938-64, undated (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - Maillart, Ella1951-88, undated (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - Majors, Alma and Lou1962-81 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - Maltz, Albert, Margaret Larkin (first wife?), and Rosemary (second wife?)1941-79, undated (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - Manchester, Evelyn1956-60 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - Mangione, Jerre and Patricia1968-87 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - Marberry, Virginia Gardner1946, 1970 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - Marjan, Korsic1951-60 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - Marsh, Benjamin C. (Box 52)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--Peoples Lobby]
    - Marshall, Atlantis1940-58, undated (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - Marshall, Dorothy1966-79, undated (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - Marshall, George1941-52, undated (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - Marshall, Scott1976-77 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Mason, Mary Bacon and Beulah MacKay1944-52, undated (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - Matthews, Doug1981-88, undated (Box 53, Folder 5)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--W.A.G.E]
    - May, Sybil1965-78 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - McAvoy, Muriel and Clifford, and Mary McAvoy Johnstone (includes snapshots of Jessie and Harvey, circa 1955)1954-61, 1981, undated (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - McConnell, Genevieve Knapp1944-54, undated (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - McCormick, Anne O'Hare (Box 53)
      [see SERIES III. WRITINGS-Articles and essays-"Two Americans Look at Russia"]
    - McCulloch, Catherine Waugh1938-44 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - McKibben, R. Norman1936, 1943 (Box 53, Folder 10)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES--American League Against War and Fascism]
    - McLean, Frannie1920-21 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - Meiklejohn, Alexander and Helen1962-65 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - Mercer, Bobby and Lyle1961-88 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Merlin, Evelyn Platt1936-51 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - Merman, Elfriede1962-65 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - Meserole, Darwin J., and Clinton, Jr. (nephew)1939-52, undated (Box 53, Folder 16-17)
    - Meyerson, Seymour and Lotte1943-79, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Milgram, Morris1978-88, undated (Box 53, Folder 19)
    - Miller, Helen Rand1945-77 (Box 53, Folder 20)
    - Miller, Mary[1955?]-62 (Box 53, Folder 21)
    - Miller, Zelma1946-62, undated (Box 54, Folder 1)
    - Mills, Doris1949-86 (Box 54, Folder 2)
      [see also SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES --WILPF]
    - Mohr, Esther and George1946-59 (Box 54, Folder 3)
    - Molinaro, Frances1979-82 (includes letter from her niece, Lillian Mahoney, 1987) (Box 54, Folder 4)
    - Moore, Lillian1969-80 (Box 54, Folder 5)
    - Moore, J. Hayden, Sr.1948-52 (Box 54, Folder 6)
    - Moos, Elizabeth1949-50 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    - Mulloy, Joe and Karen1960-67 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    - Muste, A.J. (Box 54)
      [see SERIES IV. ORGANIZATION FILES-Liberation]
    - Mygatt, Tracy D.1947-73 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    - M1918-84, undated (Box 54, Folder 10)
    - Nathan, Otto1970-84 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    - Nearing, Scott and Helen1946-67 (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - Neil, Rebecca1946-53 (Box 54, Folder 13)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL -Homes and other real estate-Jamaica (Bu Saaba]
    - Nobel, Jim and Ruth1944-67 (Box 54, Folder 14)
    - Nold, Andrea1966-67 (Box 54, Folder 15)
    - N1925-71, undated (Box 54, Folder 16)
    - O'Flaherty, Frances1938-75, undated (Box 54, Folder 17)
      [see also SERIES I. BIOGRAPHICAL MATERIAL-Financial and legal material-The Lloyd Properties]
    - Olson, Harry and Marion1980-87, undated (Box 54, Folder 18)
    - O'R-----, Warren1946-47 (Box 54, Folder 19)
    - Oster, Bernard and Daphnecirca 1970, 1972, undated (Box 54, Folder 20)
    - Otter, Paula1920-21 (Box 54, Folder 21)
    - Otto, Irma1951-75, undated (Box 54, Folder 22)
    - Otto, Sarah1958 (Box 54, Folder 23)
    - O1920s?-77 (Box 54, Folder 24)
    - Palmer, Frank L.1931-36, undated (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Palthe-Braese, Mien1930-58, undated (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Papaandreu, Eulalia Figueiredo1951-86, undated (Box 55, Folder 3)
      [see also France, Clemens; SERIES V. SUBJECT FILES -Political prisoners and refugees-Papaandreu, Eulalia Figueiredo]
    - Pappenheim, Yvonne1971-88, undated (Box 55, Folder 4)
    - Papworth, John1958-88 (Box 55, Folder 5)
    - Parent, Polly and Gaileundated (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Park, Alice1930-56 (Box 55, Folder 7)
    - Parker, Virginia1947-78, undated (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Parkhurst, Minnie, and May Wysong1963-72 (Box 55, Folder 9)
    - Parks, Ruth and Amy1951-56 (Box 55, Folder 10)
    - Parmelee, Foster1963?-1981 (Box 55, Folder 11)
    - Parmelee, Maurice1950-66 (Box 55, Folder 12)
    - Paull, Lucia1949-57, undated (Box 55, Folder 13)
    - Paz, Frank and Sarah1946-60 (Box 55, Folder 14)
    - Peck, Doris1968-[72] (Box 55, Folder 15)
    - Peck, Sidney, Louise, and Sylviacirca 1971-82, undated (Box 55, Folder 16)
    - Peters, Olga Winstead1938-88 (Box 55, Folder 17)
    - Phelps, Faye1952-80 (Box 55, Folder 18)
    - Phillips, Cecile1928-80, undated (Box 55, Folder 19)
    - PhillipsJan, 1977-83, undated (Box 55, Folder 20)
    - Phillips, Mary1959-63 (Box 55, Folder 21)
    - Phillips, Terrill and Becky1962-71 (Box 55, Folder 22)
    - Piel, Eleanor and Gerard1962-78 (Box 55, Folder 23)
    - Platt, Evelyn (Box 55)
      [see Merlin, Evelyn Platt]
    - Pollard, Jennie O. [re: her sister, Louise Olivereau]1965 (Box 55, Folder 24)